Killian Jochen McShane

Computer Science Student

killian.jmcshane@gmail.com github.com/killianmcshane in killianmcshane.github.io +44 7821745056

Second-year student of computer science at The University of Liverpool, specialising in artificial intelligence and data science. Proficient in R, Python, Java, SQL, and functional Haskell programming languages with experience using software development and data analysis tools such as Apache Ant and Tableau. I am highly IT and Mathematically literate, with a strong background in customer-facing roles.

Education

BSc (Hons) Computer Science

The University of Liverpool

09/2018 - Present

First Class (Expected)

Career

Customer Service Representative

The Royal Bank of Scotland

10/2017 - 03/2018

Relfact

- High-pressure environment with heavy call queues, and complex verbiage.
- Teamwork, exceeding KPI expectations and preventing escalations was necessary to succeed.
- Asking pertinent questions and empathetically delivering help was key to resolving issues quickly.

Customer Service Representative

Teleperformance UK

10/2016 - 04/2017

Newry

- · Handled and managed customer complaints.
- Discussing payment options, credit management and answering general enquiries.
- Building rapport with customers.

Data Analysis Spring Internship

FM Environmental

04/2015

Newry

- First-hand experience of the duties of an engineer.
- Analysed and processed friction and fluid calculations.
- Graphed insights from data analysis using Excel to relay information to engineers.

Languages

English
 Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German
 Professional Working Proficiency

Skills



Achievements

Founder & President of The Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Society at The University of Liverpool

I manage the society's conduct and the organisation of the group as a whole. My leadership involves chairing meetings, attracting funding, and managing relationships with stakeholders.

BT Young Scientist Boot Camp (2015)

Selected for and won the competition. Lead a team of 5 individuals through the development lifecycle of a new product.

British Heart Foundation CPR Certified

Interests

Boxing	Running		Mathe	ematics
Deep Learning		Big Data		Crypto & Blockchain

References

- Mrs Kay Arrowsmith BSc (Hons) PGCE
 Associate Lecturer at University of Liverpool
 0151 794 2000
- Mr Jed Goldsag
 Line Manager at The Royal Bank of Scotland
 03457 242424